(サクラ)失礼します。
Excuse me!
(綱手)よし 入れ。
Enter.
(サクラ)全員 集合しました。
Everyone's here.
(ナルト)あれ 父ちゃんは？
Huh?
Where's my dad?
今朝から各里の代表が集まって→
Representatives from each village
have been in an emergency session
since morning.
緊急会議が開かれている。
四代目も カカシたち上忍を連れて
参加している。
Lord Fourth took Kakashi and
the other jonin with him…
They're participating as well.
どうりで… うっ！
(自来也)ナルト。
No wonder…
Naruto! I'm here too.
わしもいるんだがのう。
エロ仙人…。
Pervy Sage!
(サクラ)綱手様
お話って何なんですか？
Lady Tsunade, what did you want
to see us about?
各地 いたるところで
ある情報が流れている。
It's regarding the news going around
in each region…
そのことについてだ。
情報… ですか。
News?
大蛇丸が死んだ。
The news that Orochimaru is dead.
どうやら うちはサスケが
やったらしい。
It seems Sasuke Uchiha did it.
わしとしても 大蛇丸を
連れ戻すつもりだったから→
I'm just disappointed because
I wanted to bring Orochimaru back.
残念でならんのだが…。
エロ仙人には悪いが
サスケが大蛇丸の→
Sorry about that, Pervy Sage…
But I'm just glad that Sasuke
didn't end up as Orochimaru's vessel.
器にならずに済んで
よかったってばよ。
そして もう１つ。
暁が忍里を襲い→
There's one more thing…
That the Akatsuki have been
attacking shinobi villages,
影や 上忍クラスの忍をさらっている。
kidnapping Kage and
jonin-class shinobi.
サスケが その暁と行動をともに
しているという情報もある。
And word is going around that Sasuke is
working alongside the Akatsuki.
そんな！
わしも信じられず→
No way!
I couldn't believe it either.
いくつもの 有力なラインで
情報を集めてみたのだが→
But I gathered intel from
several trusted sources…
どうやら 本当のことらしい。
and it seems to be true.
今頃 暁とサスケに対する制裁決議が
採択されていることだろう。
Around now, they're probably
adopting a resolution
to sanction the Akatsuki and Sasuke.
(サクラ)それって サスケ君が
お尋ね者になるってことですか？
Does that mean Sasuke will
become a wanted criminal?
What did Dad say?
父ちゃんは 何て言ってんだ？
無論 四代目にとって
それは 本意ではない。
Naturally, Lord Fourth would not
want that…
そこでだ。
And so…
これが 可能なかぎり集めた
情報のすべてだ。
Here's all the data we've gathered.
暁のメンバー その特徴。
The members of Akatsuki,
their special abilities
そして 彼らが出没した
場所などが書かれてある。
and where they have been spotted.
これを頼りに 他里より
早くサスケを見つけ出し→
Use this to find Sasuke before any
of the other villages, and bring him back.
連れ戻すんだ。
(自来也)それだけが サスケを救う
たった１つの方法だのう。
That's probably the only way
to save Sasuke.
(キバ)いいか？
俺たちが探索班として→
Got that?
We'll be the tracking team to help
each team locate Sasuke!
それぞれの班について
サスケの手がかりを探す。
(ヒナタ)単独行動は控え
一緒に行動してください。
Do not take action on your own.
We must work together.
(シノ)なぜなら あくまで
サスケを発見し→
The reason is because our objective
is to find Sasuke
里へ連れ戻すのが 目的だからだ。
and bring him back to the village.
That's it.
(ネジ)特にナルト 先走るんじゃないぞ。
Especially Naruto, don't go
rushing off on your own.
そんなこと わかってる。
I know that.
よっしゃ 行くってばよ！
All right, let's go!
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
The Shinobi Unite
(飛段)おっ 何だ こりゃ？
Hey!
What is this?
俺の芸術 人傀儡だ。
My art…my Human Puppets.
その数 すでに
数万にも達していよう。
They number in the several
tens of thousands.
(飛段)俺たちが集めた人材で
こんなもん作ってたのか。
You've been making stuff like this
with the personnel we gathered?
(角都)戦力を増強し
何に使うつもりだ？
All this military build-up…
What are you going to use it for?
忍の五大里に代わり
暁が世界を支配する。
We Akatsuki, will rule the world
instead of the Five Great Nations.
まずは 木ノ葉隠れの里を潰す。
First, we will crush
Hidden Leaf Village.
(デイダラ)数を頼みの物量作戦か。
So your strategy is to win with quantity?
オイラとは芸術センスが違うな。
Your perception of what art is
differs from mine.
やっぱ 芸術は
瞬間の爆発だろうが！
Art has to be an explosion!
デイダラ お前の空爆で敵を
機能不全に陥らせたところへ→
Deidara, your aerial attack will disorient
and disorganize the enemy.
人傀儡軍団を送り込み
白兵戦に持ち込む。
I'll then send in
my Human Puppet army
and there will be
an all-out ground battle.
フン オイラの芸術が
爆発したあとには→
After my artful explosion,
there won't even be a blade of grass left.
ペンペン草も生えねえ。
バカか オメエは！
Are you stupid?
それじゃ支配することには
ならねえだろうが！
Then there won't be anything left to rule!
何を!? テメエ オイラの芸術に
何か文句でもあんのかよ!?
What?
You got a problem with my art, damn it?
(飛段)大ありだ このバーカ！
You're done, you idiot!
望みどおり
木ノ葉を潰すっていうのに→
I'm letting you handle
the destruction of the Leaf,
just as you wanted.
なんか不満か？
Are you still unsatisfied?
(サスケ)俺が潰したいのは→
I just want to destroy
the current system
四代目火影を頂点とする
現体制のみ。
that has the Fourth Hokage
at its helm.
木ノ葉そのものを
潰すつもりはない。
I have no intention of crushing
the Leaf Village itself.
暁を抜けるつもりか？
Are you planning on
deserting the Akatsuki?
もともと お前の配下に
入ったつもりはない。
In the first place,
I never agreed to be your henchman.
死にかけてるところを
看病してもらったのに→
We took care of you when
you were almost dead…
裏切るってのか？
And you're gonna betray us now?
結界を破り 暁の領域に
踏み込んだ者たちがいる。
A few of them have
broken the barrier
and slipped into Akatsuki territory.
おそらく 五大里
いずれかの追っ手だ。
The Five Great Nations probably sent them.
(赤丸)ワンワン！
おお お前も におうか 赤丸。
So you caught
the scent too, eh, Akamaru?
ワン！
見つけた サスケは近いぞ。
Found him! Sasuke is close by.
ホントに サスケ君のにおいなの？
どっちだ？
Is it really Sasuke's scent?
Which way?
ついて来い。
ワン！
Follow me!
暁…。
The Akatsuki!
Sasuke…
(イタチ)サスケ。
兄さん！ 死んだはずじゃ…。
Big Brother?!
I thought you died…
(イタチ)お前を そして うちはの
未来を決められないまま→
How can I leave, when your future,
and the future of
the Uchiha Clan is in flux?
いくわけにはいかない。
しかし 傷を癒やすのに
思った以上の時間が必要だった。
Healing from my wounds
took longer than I expected.
無事で よかった。
I'm glad you're okay.
サスケ お前は
何をしようとしているんだ…。
Sasuke, what are you trying to do?
お前の居場所は どこにある？
それは…。
Where is it that you belong?
That's…
お前は すでにどう動くべきか
わかっているはずだ。
You should already know
what you must do…
サスケは サスケは 一緒じゃねえのかよ。
Where's Sasuke?
Isn't Sasuke with you?!
さっきまではいたよ。 でも
俺のやり方が気に食わねえって→
He was with us until a little while ago.
But he didn't care for the way
we do things and took off.
どっか行っちまったようだな。
こんなヤツらと
グダグダ話してたって ラチが明かねえ。
Talking with these guys
won't do anything.
さっさと 殺しちまおうぜ。
Let's just kill 'em off.
You're the one from that village…
お前 たしか あの村で…。
Oh, I remember you!
あっ 思い出したぜ。
オメエには 借りがあったんだよな。
It's payback time.
コイツら俺にやらせてくれ。
ああ 好きにしな。
Let me have this one.
Sure, do whatever you like.
ナルト君。
ああ みんな来たか。
Naruto!
Huh? You're all here.
ええ。 白眼で
ナルト君を追いかけてきたから。
Yes, I tracked you with my Byakugan.
(シカマル)飛段だな？
俺たちに任せとけ。
That's Hidan, right? Leave him to us.
でもよ…。
But—!
なに 綱手様の資料で
コイツの術は頭に入ってる。
Don't worry!
Thanks to Lady Tsunade's data,
I have his jutsu all figured out.
影首縛りの術。
Shadow Strangle Jutsu!
Hey, I'm not falling for that trick!
おっと その手には かからねえよ。
You're not getting away from us!
逃がすかよ！
(いの)ええ。
- Yeah!
- Right!
(ゼツ)飛段行っちゃったよ。
どうする？
Hidan's gone. What do we do?
ここは 相棒のお前が 何とかしろ。
You're his partner. Do something.
誰が あんなヤツの相棒だ。
チッ しかたねえな。
Who are you calling his partner?
Guess I have no choice…
アイツの名は たしか 角都。
I think his name is Kakuzu.
綱手様の資料によると→
According to Lady Tsunade's intel,
he has five hearts.
アイツは ５つの心臓を持っている。
俺の柔拳で対応できるはずだ。
My Gentle Fist should
be able to handle that.
(テンテン)私たちに
できることはないの？
Is there anything we can do?
ヤツは 中距離攻撃を得意とする。
He specializes in mid-range attacks.
それに対し柔拳は 短距離攻撃。
Gentle Fist is a short-range attack.
(リー)わかりました。 僕たちが
陽動で ヤツの意識をそらします。
Got it.
We'll create a diversion
and distract him.
その間に ネジ 頼んだわよ。
In that time, Neji…take him down!
行くわよ！
Here I go!
逃げようったって
そうはいきません！
You can try to run, but it's useless!
(デイダラ)いよいよ
オイラの芸術の出番だ。
It's finally time for my art to
make an appearance.
何だってばよ あれ…。
資料に目を通してないの？
What is that?!
Didn't you read through the data?
あ… ああ…。
Uh, no.
The C2 Dragon.
Ｃ２ドラゴン。
デイダラは 爆破のプロらしいわ。
Deidara is an explosives expert.
(デイダラ)それを言うなら→
If you're gonna compliment me,
I wish you'd say
I'm an "explosive artist."
一瞬にかける芸術家
とでも言ってほしいな。
Quit messing around!
ふざけたこと言ってんじゃねえ！
ヘッ！ 何だ？ これ。
Huh? What is this?
(サクラ)気をつけて ナルト！
Watch out, Naruto!
おっと ソイツは地雷だ。
Whoa, there! That's a landmine!
一歩でも動けば
オイラの芸術が弾けるぜ。
One step and my art will go off!
げっ… くっ… クソッ！
Damn it!
サスケ!?
Sasuke?
あ～っ!!
あれ？ 爆発しないぞ。
What? There was no explosion!
ちっ！
雷遁で地雷を無効化しやがったか。
He used Lightning Style to
deactivate the land mines!
サスケ 大蛇丸を倒したんなら
どうして すぐ里に戻らねえ。
Why didn't you return to the village
right after you brought
down Orochimaru?!
いつでも俺が
相手をしてやるっつうのによ。
I would have been happy to
take you on any time.
話は コイツらを倒してからだ。
We can talk after we finish these guys.
って お前の仲間じゃねえのかよ？
They aren't your comrades?!
目的が異なる者たちを
仲間とは呼ばない。
Ones who don't share
my goal aren't my comrades.
なら 話は早い。
Then that makes it easy.
上のヤツは 俺たちに任せろ。
Leave the ones up top, to us!
いくぜ 赤丸。
ワン！
Let's go, Akamaru!
牙通牙！
Fang Over Fang!
へっ。
今だ 赤丸！
Now, Akamaru!
ワン！
おっ!?
(キバ)ダイナミックマーキング！
Dynamic Marking!
うわっ 汚ぇ！
なんて 芸術センスのカケラもねえ術だ。
Ew, that's disgusting!
That jutsu didn't even have
one fragment of art to it!
もう許さねえ。
I can't stand it anymore…
I'll show you what real art is!
お前らに
本物の芸術を見せてやる。
フンッ 芸術なんて クソ食らえだ。
To hell with art!
あっ 待て コノヤロー！
Hey, wait! You bastard!
なんで 助けてくれたんだ？
Why did you save me?
Because I'll be the one
to take you down.
お前を倒すのは 俺だからな。
へっ。
話は 暁を始末したあとだ。
ああ そうだな。
We'll talk after
we take care of the Akatsuki.
All right.
これは
まずいんじゃないでしょうか。
This doesn't look good,
don't you think?
巻き込まれないうちに
静かに退場だ。
Let's get out of here quietly
before we get dragged into this.
チッ。
お前一人になっちまったな。
Now it's only you.
サスケ お前には 失望したぜ。
Sasuke, I'm disappointed in you.
死ね！
Die!
しゃんなろ～！
Cha!
Chidori!
千鳥！
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
(サソリ)クッ ハハハッ
久しぶりだな 表に出たのは。
It's been a long time since
I've been outside.
What?!
なに!?
(サソリ)お前たちを人傀儡にして
暁の仲間にしてやるよ。
I'm gonna turn you into Human Puppet
comrades of the Akatsuki.
お前の仲間になんか なるもんか。
We'll never become your comrades!
さて それは どうかな。
Well, we'll see about that.
口寄せ 穢土転生。
Summoning Jutsu…
Reanimation!
なっ 何だ？ あれは。
W-What is this?
(サソリ)大蛇丸が生きていたときに→
Shinobi Puppet Users that Orochimaru
and I prepared
ヤツと用意した傀儡使いの忍たち。
while he was still alive.
３年前 ヒザシをよみがえらせたのと
同じ術だ。
It's the same jutsu that was
used three years ago
to resurrect Hizashi.
更に…。
On top of that…
(サソリ)どうだ？
Well, how do like it?
これが これからの忍世界を
支配する 俺の芸術→
This is my art
that will rule the Shinobi World
from now on…
人傀儡部隊だ。
…the Human Puppet Army.
な… なんて数なの？
S-So many of them…
でも やるしかねえってばよ。
We have no choice
but to destroy them…
(テマリ)忍法 カマイタチ！
Ninja Art: Wind Scythe Jutsu!
父ちゃん！ それに みんなまで！
It's Dad!
And everyone!
(ミナト)急を聞いて
会議の場から駆けつけたんだよ。
I rushed over from the summit
as soon as I heard.
(我愛羅)友の危機を
放ってはおけないからな。
We can't ignore a friend, after all.
我愛羅！
Gaara!
(カンクロウ)傀儡のことなら
俺たちはエキスパートじゃん。
When it comes to puppets,
we're experts.
(テマリ)私たちが相手になってやる。
We'll take you on.
(カンクロウ)チャクラの糸を狙え！
Aim for the Chakra Threads!
そうすれば
コイツらは ただの人形じゃん。
Do that and these guys
become mere puppets!
ナルト お前はサソリを頼む。
Naruto, you deal with Sasori.
ああ！
Right!
これで お前一人だってばよ。
Now, it's just you.
コイツが お前らの相手だ。
He'll be your opponent.
あれは まさか!?
Impossible! Is that—?!
一瞬で終わらせる。
It will all be over in an instant.
サクラちゃん？
Sakura…?
私だって 修業して
２人に追いついたんだから。
I trained hard too, and caught up
to both of you.
それに 今… 溜まりきった。
And besides…
it's full now.
とにかく 見てて。
Anyway…just watch!
しゃんなろ～！
Cha!
す すげぇ…。
フンッ！
Wow…!
じゃあ これならどうかな？
Well then, how about this?
これは…。
そんな…。
They're!
No way! Current Kage were turned
into Human Puppets too?!
今の影たちまで人傀儡に？
コイツらを人傀儡にするのは
苦労した。
I had a hard time turning them
into Human Puppets.
多くの戦力も失った。
I lost a lot of military strength
because of that…
その穴埋めのため サスケ
お前を暁に招き入れたのだが…。
To make up for the loss, Sasuke…
I brought you into the Akatsuki.
さっさと
人傀儡にしておくんだったな。
I should've turned you into
a Human Puppet right from the beginning!
ってことは… サスケ君は無実？
So that means…
Sasuke's innocent?
そんなことは どうでもいい。
That doesn't matter.
今は 目の前の敵に集中しろ！
Right now, focus on the enemy
in front of us.
(ミナト)今だよ！
Now!
これであらかた封印したが…。
All right, they're sealed.
(ナルトたち)口寄せの術！
- Summoning Jutsu!
カツユ様 私たちは みんなの回復を！
Lady Katsuyu, we'll work
on everyone's recovery!
俺たちは 影をやるってばよ！
And we'll handle the Kage!
フン。
えっ ちょ 一人で？
Why are you going in alone?!
I'll settle this by myself!
俺 一人でカタをつける！
塵遁 原界剥離の術！
Particle Style:
Atomic Dismantling Jutsu!
What?!
アオダが一撃で…。
He took out Aoda in one hit?
どうだ
これこそ美しい芸術だろう。
See?
Isn't that what you call art?
これで お前たちも
俺の芸術の仲間入りだ！
Now you can become part of my art!
Hold on a minute!
(自来也)あいや しばらく！
ん？
エロ仙人！
Pervy Sage?!
チーム・ジライヤ ここに見参！
Team Jiraiya is on the scene!
長門 小南！
Nagato? Konan?
(長門)約束どおり 仲間を
助けることができたらしいな。
It seems you were able to save
your comrade as you promised.
あぁ まだ仲直り… とまでは
いってねえけどな。
Y-Yeah!
Although we haven't quite made up yet.
(小南)じゃあ これで
ナルト あなたは…。
Then Naruto, you're…
あぁ 弥彦は死んでしまったが
お前が その代わりだ。
Yeah…
Yahiko is dead,
but you're his replacement.
それって…。
That's…
チーム・ジライヤ 再結成だのう。
Team Jiraiya is back!
忍の未来を担う予言の子の共演
見せてもらうぞ！
The Child of Prophecy who will
save the future of shinobi…
Let's see what you can do!
アハ… あぁ！
Okay!
Lava Style:
溶遁 溶怪の術！
Lava Monster Jutsu!
あっけなかったな。
How disappointing…
クッ…。
油断しすぎだぞ サスケ。
You're too reckless, Sasuke.
兄さん…。
Big Brother?
なぜ 一人で戦おうとする。
お前には仲間がいるだろう。
フッ とにかく今は
俺が協力してやる。
好きにしろ。
いけ ガマ吉！
これは ヤバイってばよ！
俺に任せろ。
塵遁 原界剥離の術！
すべての術は吸収する。
今だ ナルト！
おう！
螺旋丸！
今だ！ サスケ！
まさか… 俺の芸術が…。
くっ… まだだ まだ終わらん！
俺は まだ負けない！
いや オメエは勝てねえよ。
何だと？
よく見てみろよ。
仲間を人形にしちまうような
ヤツには ぜってぇ勝てねえ。
俺の仲間にはな！
フン… くだらん。
風遁 螺旋手裏剣！
炎遁 加具土命！
(２人)うお～！
うわぁ！
終わったな。
サスケ 里に戻ってきてくれ。
そして もう一度
一からやり直して→
友達になれねえかな。
ああ 木ノ葉には戻る。
だが 勘違いするな。
えっ？
お前たちと手を組むつもりはない。
俺は 俺のやり方で
忍世界を変える。
皆様 お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
今日も 皆さんに
喜んでいただける歌を→
選んだつもりです。
どうぞ最後まで
ごゆっくりご覧ください。
＜今回のオープニングは
力強く 華々しくまいります！
氷川きよしさん 三山ひろしさん
夢の競演です。
まずは この曲
『きよしのズンドコ節』＞